export const usHist1302Data = {
  "voiceovers":{
    "Chapter 32":[
      {
        "Question": "A group that was very angry about the masssive bailouts of huge banks and corporations after 07-08 econimic metldown and who wanted a radically smaller government was called",
        "Answer": "the Tea Party"
      },
      {
        "Question": "What 2013 Supreme Court Case gutted key provisions of the Voting Act of 1965, making it more difficult for certain groups to vote in certain areas?",
        "Answer": "Shelby v. Holder"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Why did the Occupy Wall Street movement begin to fade?",
        "Answer": "It was leaderless, and had no specific goals"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Who was called the \"Deporter in Chief\" because under his administration, record numbers of illegal aliens were deported",
        "Answer": "Barack Obama"
      },
      {
        "Question": "During the Arab Awakening, what became the main stumbling block for installing democratic governemnts",
        "Answer": "the unwillingness to allow freedom of religion"
      }
    ],
    "Chapter 17":[
      {
        "Question": "What did the Munn v. Illinois case do?",
        "Answer": "ruled that when a private company's business affected the public, the public has the right to regulate that business for the common good."
      },
      {
        "Question": "What did the Wabash Case do?",
        "Answer": "ruled that only Congress can regulate commerce between and among the states."
      },
      {
        "Question": "What were 2 reasons why the cattle industry was stifled early on?",
        "Answer": "because the Civil War began, because Missouri passed a law making it illegal to import cattle from Texas"
      },
      {
        "Question": "In 1866, when the Transcontinental railroad reached Abilene, Kansas, who decided to take advantage of the situation and ship cattle on the Kansas Pacific Railroad?",
        "Answer": "Joseph G. McCoy"
      },
      {
        "Question": "What did the book, A Century of Dishonor, lead to?",
        "Answer": "the Dawes Severalty Act"
      }
    ],
    "Chapter 18":[
      {
        "Question": "Were the Molly Maguires successful in getting the needs of the coal miners addressed?",
        "Answer": "No"
      },
      {
        "Question": "What law was passed requiring all Chinese residents of the U.S. to carry a resident permit?",
        "Answer": "Geary Act"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Which labor Union was very secretive, and allowed both skilled and unskilled workers to join?",
        "Answer": "Knights of Labor"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Which labor union only allowed skilled workers to join, and even derailed the attempts of unskilled laborers to unionize?",
        "Answer": "American Federation of Labor"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Which President was the first to have electrical illumination and the first to have a telephone in the White House?",
        "Answer": "Hayes"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Who introduced the idea of having only 4 time zones?",
        "Answer": "Charles F. Dowd"
      },
      {
        "Question": "What is one thing that is NOT true about the Pacific Railway Act?",
        "Answer": "It required railroads to be consolidated."
      },
      {
        "Question": "Which two men worked together to bring order out of chaos and consolidate railroads, though they might have labored outside of the law to do so?",
        "Answer": "J. Edgar Thompson and Cornelius Vanderbilt"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Which business titan created the first monopoly, ending up with 90% of the oil refining capacity in America?",
        "Answer": "John D. Rockefeller"
      },
      {
        "Question": "What business titan created the first billion dollar corporation - U.S. Steel?",
        "Answer": "J.P. Morgan"
      }
    ],
    "Chapter 19":[
      {
        "Question": "The reformers who called for good government were called the __ by the political machines. 10 points",
        "Answer": "Goo Goos"
      },
      {
        "Question": "British philosopher __ came up with the idea of Social Darwinism, which led to brutal business practices.",
        "Answer": "Herbert Spencer"
      },
      {
        "Question": "One thing NOT true about the Grandfather Clause was __.",
        "Answer": "If your grandfather had owned land before Reconstruction then you could, vote without paying the poll tax."
      },
      {
        "Question": "Birds of Passage were people who came to America __.",
        "Answer": "for the job opportunities. They did not plan to stay."
      },
      {
        "Question": "What was NOT a reason discussed for the first 3 waves to oppose the 4th wave of immigrants?",
        "Answer": "People felt they took all of the good land available"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Why did Grover Cleveland veto the literacy bill that Congress passed in 1896?",
        "Answer": "He said that it tested prior opportunity, and America was a land of opportunity."
      },
      {
        "Question": "What groups did the National Origins Act NOT affect negatively?",
        "Answer": "Northern and Western Europeans"
      },
      {
        "Question": "According to the voice over, in the 1880s, the rural population increased by 5 million, but the urban population increased by __.",
        "Answer": "40 million"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Architect __ designed dumbell tenements, which attempted to fix the problem of airlessness in inner apartments.",
        "Answer": "James Ware"
      },
      {
        "Question": "African American boxer __, from Galveston, was nationally known by 1902.",
        "Answer": "Jack Johnson"
      }
    ],
    "Chapter 20":[
      {
        "Question": "According to the voice over, what percentage of eligible voters was exercising the right to vote during the late 19th century?",
        "Answer": 80
      },
      {
        "Question": "During the late 19th century, if a presidential or vice presidential nominee was from Illinois, Indiana, Ohio, or New York, he was likely chosen as a candidate because __.",
        "Answer": "his was a swing state."
      },
      {
        "Question": "Giteau assassinated Garfield because __.",
        "Answer": "he was passed over by Garfield for a position in the new government."
      },
      {
        "Question": "The Act that established a commission to provide testing for lower level government positions, thereby helping to get rid of a lot of patronage positions, was the __.",
        "Answer": "Pendleton Act"
      },
      {
        "Question": "The presidential candidate who was found to have fathered an illegitimate child in his youth was __.",
        "Answer": "Grover Cleveland"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Farmers in the late 19th century were calling for __, which would inflate the currency.",
        "Answer": "Bimetallism"
      },
      {
        "Question": "The big event that put Eugene Debs into prison and which led to his eventually embracing Socialism was __.",
        "Answer": "The Pullman Strike"
      },
      {
        "Question": "The issue of bimetallism was portrayed in The Wizard of Oz novel using __.",
        "Answer": "Dorothy's silver slippers walking down the Yellow Brick Road"
      },
      {
        "Question": "The government passed the __, which attempted unsuccessfully to regulate big businesses.",
        "Answer": "Sherman Anti-Trust Act"
      },
      {
        "Question": "The presidential candidate who traveled to 28 states and over 13,000 miles in a whistlestop campaign by train was __.",
        "Answer": "William Jennings Bryan"
      }
    ],
    "Chapter 21":[
      {
        "Question": "Turner's Thesis said that the frontier had brought all of the following things EXCEPT:",
        "Answer": "Manifest Destiny"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Those people who wanted to have Hawaii annexed into the U.S. included __.",
        "Answer": "American sugar planters in Hawaii"
      },
      {
        "Question": "One thing that was NOT a reason that many Americans wanted to get involved in what would become the Spanish-American War was _.",
        "Answer": "Spain's attempt to give the Cubans autonomy, but not independence"
      },
      {
        "Question": "The author of The Influence of Seapower Upon History was __.",
        "Answer": "Alfred Thayer Mahan"
      },
      {
        "Question": "The Teller Amendment __.",
        "Answer": "declared that the U.S. had no economic or territorial interest in Cuba"
      },
      {
        "Question": "The U.S. decided to keep the Philippines, which prompted a war that was led on the Filipino side by __.",
        "Answer": "Emilio Aguinaldo"
      },
      {
        "Question": "What country became an American Territory at the end of the Spanish American War, and its people later became American citizens?",
        "Answer": "Puerto Rico"
      },
      {
        "Question": "The Platt Amendment __.",
        "Answer": "gave the U.S. the right to intervene in Cuba"
      },
      {
        "Question": "The Open Door Policy__.",
        "Answer": "declared China open to trade from all nations"
      },
      {
        "Question": "The 9th and 10th U.S. Cavalry regiments were __ regiments during the Spanish American War who won the Battle of San Juan Hill but were not recognized for it.",
        "Answer": "African American"
      }
    ],
    "Chapter 22":[
      {
        "Question": "The group most involved in effecting progressive reform was the __.",
        "Answer": "Middle Class"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Which of the following was NOT a characteristic of progressivism?",
        "Answer": "Radicalism"
      },
      {
        "Question": "The Shame of the Cities, by __, found that many cities were corrupt and poorly run, and led to a call for municipal reform.",
        "Answer": "Lincoln Steffens"
      },
      {
        "Question": "The 17th Amendment was eventually passed after __ wrote about politicians being given kickbacks from big corporations.",
        "Answer": "David Philips"
      },
      {
        "Question": "The Galveston Plan involved __.",
        "Answer": "electing a city council and hiring a nonpolitical city manager."
      },
      {
        "Question": "Upton Sinclair was hoping to __.",
        "Answer": "highlight the problems with capitalism and encourage socialist reform"
      },
      {
        "Question": "The Triangle Shirtwaist Fire __.",
        "Answer": "led to new workplace safety laws being passed."
      },
      {
        "Question": "The _ was formed jointly by African Americans and white progressives, and became the most important civil rights organization in the country, attempting change by going through the court system.",
        "Answer": "NAACP"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Many progressives were reluctant to support the _.",
        "Answer": "Feminist Movement"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Boxer Jack Johnson was wrongly indicted under the _.",
        "Answer": "Mann Act"
      }
    ],
    "Chapter 23":[
      {
        "Question": "The Oregon System included all of the following EXCEPT:",
        "Answer": "Brains Trust"
      },
      {
        "Question": "The Wisconsin Idea was implemented by _.",
        "Answer": "Bob LaFollette"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Teddy Roosevelt referred to the presidency as a _, which was the idea that the presidency was a forum for ideas and leadership of the nation.",
        "Answer": "bully pulpit"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Teddy Roosevelt invited _ to have dinner at the White House, which upset Southern Democrats.",
        "Answer": "Booker T. Washington"
      },
      {
        "Question": "This President initiated 90 anti-trust suits during his time in office.",
        "Answer": "Taft"
      },
      {
        "Question": "The _ Act authorized the ICC to set maximum rates that railroads could charge, helping to regulate the railroads at last.",
        "Answer": "Hepburn Act"
      },
      {
        "Question": "All of the political parties except the __ had a candidate in the 1912 election.",
        "Answer": "Communists"
      },
      {
        "Question": "The act that restructured the nation's banking and currency system was the _ Act.",
        "Answer": "Federal Reserve"
      },
      {
        "Question": "The progressive President who was not so progressive in the area of race relations, allowing segregation in federal offices, was _.",
        "Answer": "Wilson"
      },
      {
        "Question": "The Presidential candidate in 1912 who ran on a campaign called New Freedom was _.",
        "Answer": "Wilson"
      }
    ],
    "Chapter 24":[
      {
        "Question": "The Panama Canal did all of the following except:",
        "Answer": "helped to improve our relationships with Latin American countries"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Dollar Diplomacy was primarily practiced by President_.",
        "Answer": "Taft"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Some people felt that __ represented democracy in Mexico.",
        "Answer": "Pancho Villa"
      },
      {
        "Question": "The event that kicked off the Great War was __.",
        "Answer": "The assassination of Archduke Ferdinand"
      },
      {
        "Question": "The Central Powers were made up of __.",
        "Answer": "Germany, Austria-Hungry, Ottoman Empire"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Germany's plan to take France in a month by going through neutral Belgium was called __.",
        "Answer": "the Schlieffen Plan"
      },
      {
        "Question": "All of these things helped bring the U.S. into World War I except:",
        "Answer": "Germany's invasion of neutral Belgium"
      },
      {
        "Question": "The food administrator who encouraged people to grow victory gardens and participate in things like Wheatless Wednesdays was:",
        "Answer": "Herbert Hoover"
      },
      {
        "Question": "The prohibition law (_ Amendment) was passed during World War I, which made it unlawful to manufacture, sell, or transport liquor.",
        "Answer": "18th"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Wilson felt that the most important of his 14 Points was:",
        "Answer": "a League of Nations"
      }
    ]
  },
  "revel":{
    "Chapter 32": [
    {
      "Question": "The presidential election of 2000 hinged on the votes of which state?",
      "Answer": "Florida"
    },
    {
      "Question": "Which of the following characterized the state of the economy during the election of 2000?",
      "Answer": "The stock market was going strong."
    },
    {
      "Question": "What did George W. Bush make the centerpiece of his economic policy?",
      "Answer": "reducing taxes"
    },
    {
      "Question": "The “No Child Left Behind” policy reflected George W. Bush’s attempt at __________ reform.",
      "Answer": "education"
    },
    {
      "Question": "Who initiated the war on terror?",
      "Answer": "George W. Bush"
    },
    {
      "Question": "Which of the following was saved from bankruptcy by the administration of George W. Bush during the Great Recession?",
      "Answer": "Freddie Mac"
    },
    {
      "Question": "The Bakke and Hopwood decisions reflect the Supreme Court’s different positions on __________.",
      "Answer": "affirmative action"
    },
    {
      "Question": "What did Obergefell v. Hodges uphold?",
      "Answer": "the right of same-sex couples to marry"
    },
    {
      "Question": "Which of the following has been offered to support the view that the election of Barack Obama aggravated racial tensions?",
      "Answer": "Some whites became resentful at seeing a black man in the White House."
    },
    {
      "Question": "Which of the following has been proposed as a way to deal with climate change?",
      "Answer": "a “carbon tax” on emissions of greenhouse gases"
    },
    {
      "Question": "Which state had more than 50 percent voter turnout in the 2016 presidential primaries?",
      "Answer": "New Hampshire"
    },
    {
      "Question": "In the early nineteenth century, those who had a right to vote had to __________.",
      "Answer": "own a certain amount of property"
    },
    {
      "Question": "In contrast to baby boomers, Millennials and Generation X get most of their news from __________.",
      "Answer": "Facebook"
    }],
    "Chapter 17": [
      {
        "Question": "Which of the following achieved statehood by the end of the nineteenth century?",
        "Answer": "Wyoming"
      },
      {
        "Question": "America’s westward expansion in the last three decades of the nineteenth century had the most negative effect on which group?",
        "Answer": "Native Americans"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Horace Greeley told New York City’s unemployed: “If you strike off into the broad, free West, and make yourself a farm from Uncle Sam’s generous domain, you will crowd nobody, starve nobody, and neither you nor your children need evermore beg for something to do.” Which of the following acts could Greeley cite to support his statement?",
        "Answer": "Homestead Act of 1862"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Which of the following describes the geographic features found in the Great Plains?",
        "Answer": "treeless, nearly flat, land"
      },
      {
        "Question": "By 1840, the line of white settlement had reached the edge of the __________.",
        "Answer": "Missouri timber country"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Which of the following made settling the Great Plains difficult?",
        "Answer": "little rainfall"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Which of the following was a Plains tribe?",
        "Answer": "the Blackfoot"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Which of the following describes the culture of the Plains Indians?",
        "Answer": "They were nomadic."
      },
      {
        "Question": "Before the Civil War, the land __________ was designated as “Indian Country” by the U.S. government.",
        "Answer": "west of the Mississippi"
      },
      {
        "Question": "According to the prophet Wovoka, the Ghost Dances would lead to __________.",
        "Answer": "unity among Native Americans"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Which of the following was the Plains Indians’ chief resource and the basis for their unique way of life?",
        "Answer": "the buffalo"
      },
      {
        "Question": "What was the westernmost endpoint of the Overland Trail?",
        "Answer": "the Pacific coast"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Which of the following marked the end of the first leg of the Overland Trail?",
        "Answer": "Fort Kearney"
      },
      {
        "Question": "The migration of which group in the second half of the nineteenth century suggests that the settlement of the West was more than a simple “westward” movement?",
        "Answer": "Mexicans moving north"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Which of the following acts offered 160 acres of land to anyone who would pay a $10 registration fee and pledge to live on the land and cultivate it for five years?",
        "Answer": "Homestead Act of 1862"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Which of the following was used in placer mining?",
        "Answer": "a washing pan"
      },
      {
        "Question": "In the first 15 years of the twenty-first century, which state drew a lot of capital investment during the boom in the oil industry?",
        "Answer": "North Dakota"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Which of the following states was the last Indian territory to be opened to white settlement?",
        "Answer": "Oklahoma"
      },
      {
        "Question": "A farmer in the American West in the late nineteenth century would most likely be a part of the __________.",
        "Answer": "National Grange of the Patrons of Husbandry"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Which part of the American Southwest produced the most agricultural goods in 1890?",
        "Answer": "California"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Which city linked the economy of the West to the economy of the Northeast in the second half of the nineteenth century?",
        "Answer": "Chicago"
      },
      {
        "Question": "In the second half of the nineteenth century, the West had a primarily __________ economy.",
        "Answer": "agricultural"
      }
    ],
    "Chapter 18": [{
      "Question": "By __________, U.S. manufacturing surpassed that of Britain, France, and Germany combined.",
      "Answer": 1900
    },
    {
      "Question": "The novelist William Dean Howells remarked, “It is in these things of iron and steel that the national genius most freely speaks.” Which of the following is an example of the “things” to which Howells refers?",
      "Answer": "Corliss engine"
    },
    {
      "Question": "Which of the following symbolized America’s status as an industrial nation?",
      "Answer": "Machinery Hall"
    },
    {
      "Question": "Which of the following groups participates in the “gig economy”?",
      "Answer": "on-demand drivers for Uber"
    },
    {
      "Question": "Which of the following characterized the railroads before the Civil War?",
      "Answer": "They were designed more to protect local interests."
    },
    {
      "Question": "Congress required which of the following to carry government freight, troops, and mail at reduced rates in exchange for federal subsidies?",
      "Answer": "railroads"
    },
    {
      "Question": "Which of the following was a trunk line in the late nineteenth century?",
      "Answer": "the Baltimore and Ohio"
    },
    {
      "Question": "As a result of the Panic of 1893, which of the following took control of the railroad industry?",
      "Answer": "J. P. Morgan and Company"
    },
    {
      "Question": "Which city became the center of the steel industry in the late nineteenth century?",
      "Answer": "Pittsburgh"
    },
    {
      "Question": "Petroleum led to the widespread use of which of the following in the early twentieth century?",
      "Answer": "kerosene lamps"
    },
    {
      "Question": "In 1882, John D. Rockefeller’s Standard Oil Company was organized as the first major __________.",
      "Answer": "trust"
    },
    {
      "Question": "Who was called the “Wizard of Menlo Park”?",
      "Answer": "Thomas Alva Edison"
    },
    {
      "Question": "What did American Sugar Refining, the Northern Securities Company, and the National Biscuit Company share in common?",
      "Answer": "They all organized their own trusts."
    },
    {
      "Question": "Which of the following most contributed to the advertising boom in the late nineteenth century?",
      "Answer": "the rotary press"
    },
    {
      "Question": "Which of the following people helped to make the department store into a national institution?",
      "Answer": "John Wanamaker"
    },
    {
      "Question": "Which of the following people entered the mail-order business in the late nineteenth century?",
      "Answer": "Richard W. Sears"
    },
    {
      "Question": "Which of the following reflects a trend in the last quarter of the nineteenth century that affected the lives of workers?",
      "Answer": "Real wages rose."
    },
    {
      "Question": "Which industry was the largest employer of women?",
      "Answer": "textile"
    },
    {
      "Question": "Of the groups listed, which one earned the most in the late nineteenth century?",
      "Answer": "clerical workers"
    },
    {
      "Question": "In contrast to the American Federation of Labor, the Cigar Makers’ Union and the Typographical Union __________.",
      "Answer": "accepted women workers"
    },
    {
      "Question": "Terence V. Powderly would agree with which of the following statements?",
      "Answer": "Union membership should be open to all laborers regardless of race, gender, or skill."
    },
    {
      "Question": "Which of the following correctly matches the person to the organization that he headed?",
      "Answer": "Samuel Gompers – American Federation of Labor"
    },
    {
      "Question": "Which of the following reflects the “iron law of wages”?",
      "Answer": "Wages are dictated by supply and demand."
    },
    {
      "Question": "Which of the following was involved in the Homestead Strike?",
      "Answer": "Amalgamated Iron and Steel Workers"
    },
    {
      "Question": "In the late nineteenth century, which part of the United States was the most industrialized?",
      "Answer": "Northeast"
    },
    {
      "Question": "In late nineteenth-century America, the government usually sided with which group in labor disputes?",
      "Answer": "management"
    },
    {
      "Question": "Which of the following characterized labor unions in late nineteenth-century America?",
      "Answer": "They had an antagonistic relationship with the government."
    }],
    "Chapter 19": [{
      "Question": "Many of the recently arrived immigrants who contributed to the urbanization of the United States in the late nineteenth century came from which part of the world?",
      "Answer": "Asia"
    },
    {
      "Question": "Which of the following contributed to the dramatic increase in the urban population in the late nineteenth century?",
      "Answer": "migration from the countryside"
    },
    {
      "Question": "Which group was most negatively affected by Jim Crow laws?",
      "Answer": "African Americans"
    },
    {
      "Question": "Which of the following expanded the city’s limits and transformed urban space in the late nineteenth century?",
      "Answer": "streetcar systems"
    },
    {
      "Question": "Which of the following would most likely have supported the mission of the Immigration Restriction League?",
      "Answer": "American Protective Association"
    },
    {
      "Question": "Which of the following is an example of an immigrant association?",
      "Answer": "National Council of Jewish Women"
    },
    {
      "Question": "Historically, anti-immigrant sentiment has been strongest during periods characterized by __________.",
      "Answer": "economic downturns"
    },
    {
      "Question": "What was the name of the Democratic Party organization that dominated city politics in New York from the 1850s to the 1930s?",
      "Answer": "Tammany Hall"
    },
    {
      "Question": "Which of the following did the Mugwumps support?",
      "Answer": "civil-service reform"
    },
    {
      "Question": "Which of the following signaled the rise of the city and new forms of leisure in the late nineteenth century?",
      "Answer": "spectator sports"
    },
    {
      "Question": "Which of the following people played an important role in the establishment of the National American Woman Suffrage Association in 1890?",
      "Answer": "Susan B. Anthony"
    },
    {
      "Question": "In which of the following cases did the Supreme Court apply the same rationale that had informed its ruling in Plessy v. Ferguson?",
      "Answer": "Cumming v. County Board of Education"
    },
    {
      "Question": "Whose strategy to achieve racial equality became known as the Atlanta Compromise?",
      "Answer": "Booker T. Washington"
    },
    {
      "Question": "What did Supreme Court decisions between 1878 and 1898 render ineffectual?",
      "Answer": "Reconstruction amendments"
    },
    {
      "Question": "What did the Jim Crow laws uphold?",
      "Answer": "racial segregation"
    },
    {
      "Question": "What did blacks who migrated to the North call the racism they encountered there?",
      "Answer": "James Crow"
    },
    {
      "Question": "Herbert Spencer developed the theory of __________.",
      "Answer": "social selection"
    },
    {
      "Question": "Who proposed a “single tax” on the “unearned increment” of land as a solution to economic inequality?",
      "Answer": "Henry George"
    },
    {
      "Question": "Which of the following did settlement houses offer?",
      "Answer": "medical care"
    },
    {
      "Question": "Of the following people, whose ideas most influenced Clarence Darrow?",
      "Answer": "Henry George"
    },
    {
      "Question": "Which part of the United States was the most urbanized in 1900?",
      "Answer": "Northeast"
    },
    {
      "Question": "By the end of the nineteenth century, there was a general sense among Americans that __________ had disappeared.",
      "Answer": "the frontier"
    },
    {
      "Question": "In 1900, the immigrant population in Texas was concentrated along the border with __________.",
      "Answer": "Mexico"
    }],
    "Chapter 20":[
      {
        "Question": "Which of the following was the most divisive issue in presidential campaigns in the 1890s?",
        "Answer": "basis of the currency"
      },
      {
        "Question": "The economic situation in the United States for most of the 1890s was most similar to that of the __________.",
        "Answer": "1930s"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Which of the following was a consequence of the depression of the 1890s?",
        "Answer": "expanded role of the presidency"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Which president vetoed more bills than all of his predecessors combined?",
        "Answer": "Grover Cleveland"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Which of the following would most Republicans have supported in the late nineteenth century?",
        "Answer": "high protective tariff"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Which of the following acts created the bipartisan Civil Service Commission?",
        "Answer": "Pendleton Act"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Which of the following was a result of the midterm elections in 1890?",
        "Answer": "The Republicans lost 78 seats in the House."
      },
      {
        "Question": "Which of the following was included in the Ocala Demands?",
        "Answer": "free coinage of silver"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Which organization came to dominate the Alliance movement in the 1890s?",
        "Answer": "National Farmers’ Alliance and Industrial Union"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Which of the following addressed the concerns raised by the Populist movement and party of the 1890s?",
        "Answer": "progressivism"
      },
      {
        "Question": "What were members of the People’s Party called?",
        "Answer": "Populists"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Which of the following occurred in 1893?",
        "Answer": "The New York stock market crashed."
      },
      {
        "Question": "The Supreme Court’s support of the use of the __________ in labor disputes gave business and government a powerful antilabor weapon that impeded union growth.",
        "Answer": "injunction"
      },
      {
        "Question": "In response to the Panic of 1893, which of the following acts did President Grover Cleveland repeal?",
        "Answer": "Sherman Silver Purchase Act"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Which of the following was a result of the elections of 1894?",
        "Answer": "The Republicans became the country’s majority party."
      },
      {
        "Question": "Which of the following was a goal of the League for the Protection of the Family?",
        "Answer": "compulsory education for children"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Which of the following reflects the influence of naturalism?",
        "Answer": "Sister Carrie"
      },
      {
        "Question": "What pen name did Samuel Langhorne Clemens use?",
        "Answer": "Mark Twain"
      },
      {
        "Question": "What was the election of 1896 called?",
        "Answer": "“battle of the standards”"
      },
      {
        "Question": "By 1896, what had silver come to symbolize?",
        "Answer": "rural values"
      },
      {
        "Question": "The nomination of William McKinley at the Republican Convention in 1896 was a victory for supporters of __________.",
        "Answer": "the gold standard"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Which of the following was a Populist proposal that was later adopted under different leadership?",
        "Answer": "direct election of U.S. senators"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Which of the following acts ended the silver controversy that had dominated the 1890s?",
        "Answer": "Gold Standard Act"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Which of the following contributed to the economic recovery that characterized the early years of the McKinley administration?",
        "Answer": "discovery of gold in Australia and Alaska"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Who became president after William McKinley’s assassination?",
        "Answer": "Theodore Roosevelt"
      },
      {
        "Question": "What did the People’s Party platform favor?",
        "Answer": "free coinage of silver"
      },
      {
        "Question": "The Farmers’ Alliance built a coalition with which group in the early 1890s?",
        "Answer": "Knights of Labor"
      },
      {
        "Question": "To whom is the following statement referring?: “No man who drags into the dust the most sacred symbols of the Christian world is fit to be president of the United States.”",
        "Answer": "William Jennings Bryan"
      }
    ],
    "Chapter 21":[
      {
        "Question": "The First United States Volunteer Cavalry was also known as the __________.",
        "Answer": "Rough Riders"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Which of the following did Puerto Rico, Guam, and the Philippines have in common at the end of the nineteenth century?",
        "Answer": "They came under the control of the United States."
      },
      {
        "Question": "Theodore Roosevelt would most likely have agreed with which of the following statements?",
        "Answer": "The United States needs colonies and a great navy to be a great power."
      },
      {
        "Question": "Which of the following would an isolationist most likely support?",
        "Answer": "abolition of the foreign service"
      },
      {
        "Question": "What motivated American farmers and industrialists to search for new overseas markets?",
        "Answer": "saturation of the domestic market"
      },
      {
        "Question": "What was Secretary of State William Henry Seward’s motivation for signing a treaty with Russia to purchase Alaska?",
        "Answer": "to pave the way for the annexation of western Canada"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Those who supported the annexation of Hawaii mainly emphasized its __________.",
        "Answer": "strategic value"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Which of the following people emphasized sea power as the key to world domination?",
        "Answer": "Alfred Thayer Mahan"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Which of the following helped stir up American public support for a war with Spain over Cuba?",
        "Answer": "yellow journalism"
      },
      {
        "Question": "In 1898, Americans blamed the sinking of the Maine on __________.",
        "Answer": "Spain"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Which of the following adopted a declaration of human rights that most countries, including the United States, signed?",
        "Answer": "United Nations"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Which of the following places was Chaplain George W. Prioleau most likely referring to when he said, “Here the Negro is not allowed to purchase over the same counter in some stores as the white man purchases over”?",
        "Answer": "Florida"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Which of the following placed Manila and the Philippines within American grasp?",
        "Answer": "Spanish-American War"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Which of the following did Andrew Carnegie, Jane Addams, Samuel Gompers, and Mark Twain share in common?",
        "Answer": "They all opposed the annexation of the Philippines."
      },
      {
        "Question": "Who led the Filipino resistance during the Philippine-American War?",
        "Answer": "Emilio Aguinaldo"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Which of the following implemented changes that prepared the Philippine Islands for self-government?",
        "Answer": "Taft Commission"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Why did the United States promote the Open Door Policy?",
        "Answer": "to expand trade in China"
      },
      {
        "Question": "What was called the “Crossroads of the Pacific”?",
        "Answer": "Hawaii"
      },
      {
        "Question": "From which country did the United States acquire the Philippine Islands?",
        "Answer": "Spain"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Which of the following did the United States acquire as a result of the Spanish-American War?",
        "Answer": "Puerto Rico"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Which of the following would most likely have supported U.S. foreign policy in the Pacific and the Caribbean in the late nineteenth century?",
        "Answer": "Alfred Thayer Mahan"
      }
    ]
    
  }
};
